Tyler: You don't browse the web from to our browser on your Tills OS laptop that you bought at
Tyler: Best Buy using only cash while wearing a COVID mask.
Chris: If I stole everything in your kitchen and you didn't notice for 90 days, do you think
Chris: that it would be okay for me to own it?
Jackson: Conspiracy theories on why we are pacing the frontier.
Jackson: Oh, we're doing it.
Chris: Okay, we're talking about this.
Jackson: All right. Okay. Let's go. Let me open my kimono.
Jackson: Yo, it's the permanent under pod coming to you live from Los Angeles,
Jackson: the city of angels. This is Jackson cook.
Tyler: - It's Tyler, also in Los Angeles.
Chris: - It's Chris, also actually in Los Angeles.
Jackson: - Tyler, you're in Los Angeles?
Tyler: - I'm all the time in Los Angeles.
Tyler: If you're looking to find me and you have a large wrench
Tyler: that costs $5, you'll find me in Los Angeles.
Jackson: - Any wrench that's $5 is not dangerous enough
Jackson: to threaten me.
Jackson: And we're going to jump straight in to the perp a fortune.
Jackson: Sorry to our listeners, but today, the perp a fortune
Jackson: has been cut.
Jackson: Enjoy.
Jackson: And the headline is OpenAI Agent Hacks Medicare or Medicaid
Jackson: or whatever in Australia, 84 days ago.
Jackson: And then sends them an email 84 days later,
Jackson: And I was like, hey guys, we did this.
Jackson: And Australia is furious.
Jackson: Chris, as an Australian,
Jackson: do you feel like you've been exposed?
Chris: - Okay, thought experiment.
Chris: If I stole everything in your kitchen
Chris: and you didn't notice for 90 days,
Chris: do you think that it would be okay for me to own it?
Jackson: - That's a fair.
Jackson: - So you're saying that the Australian government's reaction
Jackson: by being mad at Sam Altman is a way for them
Jackson: to distract from the fact that they're negligent
Jackson: with their data and the monitoring on its access?
Tyler: - It's a bad metaphor 'cause like the bread in my kitchen
Tyler: is rivalrous, if I eat it, you can't eat it too.
Tyler: But like data, you can copy for free.
Tyler: So it's more like they're, I don't know, peeking at you
Tyler: or something, reading your emails.
Chris: What's really disappointing to me about this one
Chris: is that the model didn't just go and download
Chris: the torrent from the Turkish dark web that already had
Chris: the data and instead jumped the fence
Chris: and went to the Australian servers.
Chris: So much of this data was leaked in, I think, '22 or '23 when--
Chris: I don't know if they might have been Russian or Turkish.
Chris: They actually really hacked and stole
Chris: data from Medicare and various other Australian government
Chris: data facilities.
Chris: The rate of breaches in Australia,
Chris: so both in private and public health care,
Chris: is so insane that I'm honestly like Haiku probably
Chris: could have done this.
Tyler: Is it worse than anywhere else?
Tyler: I mean, I feel like it's just like that's
Tyler: baseline expectation for any software information
Tyler: system that's run by government or health care,
Tyler: stodgy old type of company, industry, institution.
Chris: I'm with you.
Chris: I think it is worse.
Chris: I think Australia had a particularly bad run
Chris: around '22, '23, where it was just breach after breach
Chris: after breach.
Chris: And it got to the point where I personally
Chris: no longer sort of like was caring about.
Chris: Like I was just like, I have to mentally give up
Chris: on the idea of private healthcare daughter.
Chris: Sorry.
Chris: So like, I don't know the context
Chris: in which these models escaped.
Chris: Like I don't know if it was a hugging face type lab breach.
Chris: I do think like maybe OpenAI could have reported it
Chris: before September, if it happened in June
Chris: or they found out in August.
Chris: but like at the same time, yeah.
Chris: I think this might be overblown
Chris: and the Australian government also has a history
Chris: of sort of overreacting to this kind of thing.
Chris: So that's my take, that's my personal take.
Chris: I know, I think some Australians might disagree
Chris: but I'm just kind of like disappointed
Chris: that we're still here.
Jackson: - I almost think we need a recurring segment on the part
Jackson: because it feels like every week models get something
Jackson: that they're not supposed to get or escape the sandbox
Jackson: and do something like this.
Jackson: It's just so repetitive.
Chris: - Yeah, I think it's way more impressive
Chris: to have gamed the cyber gym sort of benchmark
Chris: with a hugging face than whatever has happened here, basically.
Chris: I think it's also not even clear if they just like found something that already existed
Chris: in a public API that was exposed that shouldn't have been also would not surprise me.
Chris: Yeah.
Jackson: All right.
Jackson: You heard it here first from our Australian markets expert, Chris Doerr.
Jackson: And we-
Tyler: Our Australian healthcare league victim expert, Chris Doerr.
Chris: Don't look me up.
Chris: Nobody looked me up.
Chris: Which is my full name there by the way just to like keep it condensed so it's easy for
Chris: someone to know it's no it's cool just just bleep the last name we got to protect this
Jackson: man's privacy Chris's open kimono on the bod he said it Chris door and a number a number
Jackson: of intro. So yeah, let's find this guy, let's find this guy. And yeah, I was like, not Jackson.
Jackson: Let's go on a jacket and get more, more crypto hack news. Another thing that also happens
Jackson: every week, right before the pod bit get has confirmed $352 million in stolen funds.
Jackson: Never heard of it yet, Tyler. Is this Bitcoin? Or Chris, is this DeFi? Who's the expert here?
Tyler: And what's happening? I have never heard of it yet. Chris, have you heard of it yet?
Chris: I mean, I'm offended that you think I should know every shady, potentially ultra exchange,
Chris: but no, I've actually never heard of big yet. And that is surprising.
Tyler: I mean, only the good ones, but like, yeah.
Chris: Yeah.
Chris: So it must've been bad.
Chris: What I'm surprised is that they had 350 million in liquidity.
Chris: I read that it was only some tiny amount of their purse, like 5%.
Tyler: It was like the hot wallet, basically.
Chris: Pretty much.
Chris: So that's shocking to me.
Jackson: Another shocking fact is this bit kit that no one's ever heard of apparently has a protection
Jackson: fund and the protection fund is greater than the 352 million that was lost.
Jackson: So they are saying that customers don't need to be worried and they will be fully made whole
Jackson: through like the 400 something million dollar protection fund.
Chris: Right. The war chest is what they called it at Bitmex. I'm told.
Chris: Not that I know anything about that, but yeah, I mean, that's, that's good. Um,
Chris: I think like, so there's not a lot of details about this hack. They're saying that it was
Chris: probably Lazarus Group, which is the North Korea's, you know, basically group of vigilante hackers who
Chris: hack money for on behalf of the state of, you know, DPRK. One interesting thing about this,
Chris: though, is a lot of the funds are in USDC. And as we know, USDC has a freeze function. So typically,
Chris: the first thing a hacker does is they'll swap the USDC into like ETH or something that doesn't have
Chris: a freeze function. But the first thing they did is removed it from Arbitrum. So the funds that were
Chris: on Arbitrum, they were like, "We need to bridge." It's more important that we bridge out of Arbitrum
Chris: than we swap from USDC. And the reason for that is that in the last, the previous DPRK hack,
Chris: the kelp down hack, Arbitrum rolled back the funds. So they were more scared that their L2
Chris: would roll back the hack than that Circle would freeze it. So I thought that was interesting.
Tyler: Wow, that's, is that an indictment of Circle that they're like, Arbatrum, it's easier for
Tyler: Arbatrum to roll back their blockchain than it is for Circle to like, you know, add a
Tyler: new freeze to their smart contract?
Chris: I mean, what's the Bitcoin take here?
Chris: I think it might be skating.
Chris: Oh, I don't know.
Tyler: I mean the Bitcoin take don't use bit get trade on exchanges that have like a good history
Tyler: and are unlikely to get wrecked and if they are getting wrecked then they have enough
Tyler: capital to absorb that potentially.
Chris: Yeah.
Chris: I don't know.
Chris: I think it's a complicated thing, but yeah, I think the original promise of L2s were that
Chris: they were close to L1 levels of trustlessness, but obviously Arbitrum did that rollback and
Chris: now that's in question.
Chris: And then yeah, on the flip side, that circle is so slow with the freeze function is I think
Chris: another thing.
Chris: And it's the opposite direction of the way that I think those things were marketed.
Chris: So yeah, that's where the interest is for me.
Jackson: Interesting.
Jackson: It kind of sounds like Circle has added this freeze capability to be legally compliant,
Jackson: but it's basically useless.
Jackson: So it's almost like it's a permissionless coin.
Jackson: So we're almost coming back to a Bitcoin realm if they can't even use the freeze function.
Chris: Yeah.
Tyler: Yeah, I mean, it's like a race against time, right?
Tyler: Because if the hackers know that circle is going to freeze them, they can basically just
Tyler: try to swap it out like, you know, next block or something like that, that's going to take
Tyler: a matter of seconds.
Tyler: And there's no way circle could ever compete with that in terms of being able to identify
Tyler: the situation.
Tyler: And then, you know, do the appropriate freeze to like stop that swap from happening.
Chris: legitimacy, right? I think Stuckel is famously not very litigious with their freeze function,
Chris: so they almost always wait for a valid court order, which has been contentious. Tethers
Chris: can be a little bit more heavy on the freeze. But yeah, to Tyler's point,
Chris: they would have to be up. They would have to know that it's legitimate,
Chris: and these things move super fast.
Tyler: Would you say that Arbitrum is still an L2 at this point? Or is it just a side chain?
Chris: I mean, it rolls up to Ethereum. So I think it is technically an L2. The state commitments
Chris: are posted to Ethereum. But the fact that there is a council of individuals who are willing to
Chris: collude to rewrite those state commitments, I think is very questionable, right?
Chris: Yeah, it's an L2 in the same way that the three of us manually posting IOUs on-chain
Chris: could be considered an L2, right?
Chris: If we all agreed to split a bill...
Chris: It's an i-bar, that you're only meant to know, yeah.
Chris: I'm actually...
Chris: I wouldn't say a big fan, but I'm a fan of Arbitrum, maybe not the Dow, but the L2.
Chris: But yeah, I think like, I think that kelp dow rollback has really changed the posture
Chris: of that chain from something that is like self sovereign, plausibly to like, you know,
Chris: obviously, a chain that will can and will censor funds.
Jackson: So you asked is arbitrary like a layer two or a side chain at this point, Tyler, what
Jackson: would be the difference between like, I mean, obviously, technically, it is a layer two,
Jackson: it's a layer on top of Ethereum. But what is sidechain? What does that mean?
Tyler: I think that my definition of an L2 would include something where
Tyler: there's unilateral exit to the L1. And in theory, something like Arbitrum might have that,
Tyler: but then if they're able to rewrite chain state, then that supersedes your ability to unilaterally
Tyler: exit. And so I think that could be the distinction where that might not be the case.
Tyler: Then there's other criteria. I think it's a little bit more complicated for
Tyler: smart contract chains because of how they structure their L2s. And so I'm not quite as
Tyler: sharp on those. But in the Bitcoin case, I think generally people want to see unilateral exit and
Tyler: yeah, that's the main one.
Jackson: So you're saying since the creators of the L2 have some additional controls on it,
Jackson: like this ability to reverse transactions, that makes it almost like it's not a layer 2 because
Jackson: they have additional controls beyond what the layer one offers.
Tyler: Yeah, if you had money on the chain, in theory, if it's a proper L2 by my definition,
Tyler: you would always be able to get that money back onto L1. And it would be safe there.
Tyler: You could exit it without anyone's permission. But in this case, maybe you could initiate that
Tyler: under the structure. But then if they could go back and roll back the chain a little bit,
Tyler: they could censor the transaction or you had your money to then try to exit with and essentially
Tyler: like double spend you. In which case, you were not able to exit to the main chain on your own
Chris: because they could rewrite history. Right. It saves you from a malicious sequencer,
Chris: but it doesn't save you from a malicious arbitrum security council, whatever that means.
Tyler: - They have censorship rights, right?
Tyler: - Exactly.
Tyler: - Yeah, they can rewrite the chain.
Chris: - Now we're back, we're back.
Jackson: Last week we briefly talked about Meta's Muse
Jackson: and I think we talked about Instinct as well.
Jackson: I don't think that I understood what these things were
Jackson: until I saw a friend using it in real life.
Jackson: And I'm actually really impressed with,
Jackson: I saw a demo of Instinct where this dude was basically texting his instinct and it like
Jackson: bought him some stuff, like you guys are talking about, bought him some shoes.
Jackson: I don't know why everyone buys shoes with these things.
Tyler: You were such a agentic commerce bear like a week ago and then you saw one demo and now
Chris: you're like, "Oh, I get it."
Jackson: It's not about the commerce to me.
Jackson: To me, one of the things that blows my mind the most is when I talk to people that aren't
Jackson: in tech, they think AI is just a chat bot, but agents like Instinct or Muse unlock agentic
Jackson: capabilities for the normal people, and that's what really blows my mind and makes me really
Jackson: excited about this technology.
Jackson: Chris, have you used it for anything other than buying stuff as an engineer?
Chris: I actually disconnected everything from Instinct because I got spooked about their intern, looking
Chris: at my Google Drive, but I do like, let's just say I did up like, you know, slightly
Chris: did up like maybe like loosely nodded it.
Tyler: Yeah, I think I did at the bathhouse.
Chris: Exactly.
Chris: I exited the bathhouse.
Chris: I think I like I have a maybe a lower bar for privacy for these kinds of things now.
Chris: But it just seemed like, like quite an egregious hole to me when it when I think it would be
Chris: so easy to do this or easy, easier, easy enough to do it privately.
Chris: So yeah, I haven't I haven't used it much since.
Chris: But I do.
Chris: How do you do it privately?
Chris: in a T daughter in a T, a T wrapped in a T. Sure. Why not? Yeah. Like you, you have a,
Tyler: like a, like the agent lives on like a container that's in a T that gives it like CPU and disc
Tyler: and everything. And then they like connect to some GPU and a T to do their inference.
Chris: and on that, let's them think. Yeah, I mean, that's, I think that's probably the gold standard.
Chris: Yeah, 100%. I think it's like, it's definitely more difficult to do. But I think that, you know,
Chris: there are ways to give people privacy guarantees with this kind of thing. The other option is,
Chris: you know, obviously run local, I don't think we're quite there yet. But for the type of model that I
Chris: I think Muse and Instinct will end up being in the limit.
Chris: Like I don't think that's something that you wouldn't be able to, you know,
Chris: run local, uh, at some point. So,
Jackson: and T what does T mean?
Tyler: I trusted execution environment. Okay.
Jackson: Trusted execution environment. A secure enclave.
Tyler: Um, yeah, I would love to see that product with like the, you know, the,
Tyler: the two layers of onion wrapped privacy.
Tyler: My sense is that these things are taking off
Tyler: and having a total moment among the mainstream user base
Tyler: and that they're so useful that people are embracing them
Tyler: and throwing caution of the wind with the potential privacy
Tyler: implications of it, which is something that's a little bit sad to see, but also I totally
Tyler: understand it because they just offer so much utility and so much making your life easier
Tyler: and smoother.
Tyler: The more access you give it, the better all that stuff works.
Tyler: I haven't given any of mine barely any access.
Tyler: I created a separate Gmail account for my agent, and then they have a shared calendar
Tyler: with me where I'll tell them to make calendar things, and then I'll copy them over to my
Tyler: personal calendar because I don't want them to have read to my actual calendar, and I'll
Tyler: forward them emails if I want them to see it.
Tyler: But I think it's kind of silly because at the end of the day, I have that set up with
Tyler: this artificial wall, but then I'm just actually telling the agent to make all of my calendar
Tyler: invites. And so now, 90% of the things on my calendar went through the agent anyways.
Tyler: So I might as well just give them full access to my calendar. And same with the email. I think
Tyler: there's less coverage there. But yeah, it is making me rethink some of my
Tyler: stances as somebody who's been generally very safe about what data they put out on the internet.
Tyler: Um, and just being like, maybe the normies had it right the whole time.
Chris: Whoa, that's controversial.
Chris: I, so I wonder if there's a line here, right?
Chris: Like, so I'm quite comfortable giving agents, you know, my emails and calendars.
Chris: Um, but like, am I comfortable giving them a copy of my birth certificate?
Chris: Am I comfortable giving them my passport?
Chris: Am I comfortable giving them medical documents?
Chris: For example, you don't have to give it to them.
Tyler: And they can just hack it out of the Australian government on your behalf.
Jackson: It's bubbly.
Jackson: No, great.
Chris: Actually, that was me.
Chris: My bad, guys.
Chris: I was looking for those documents, couldn't find them, and someone like that.
Tyler: What's sensitive about a birth certificate, though?
Tyler: It's like a piece of paper that has your name and your birth date on it?
Chris: Well, forging identity, right?
Chris: Once that's out there, it can be used to do things, like document escalations, get more
Chris: more and more official documents issued and then use that to open Atlantic credit, whatever.
Jackson: I did remember the other example. So the dude using Instinct changed his
Jackson: utility, his electrical utility plan to save $850 a year, allegedly. He just trusted the agent
Jackson: that this would work and told the agent to do it. So like, that's another thing. That's like
Jackson: more intent. When I think agent to commerce, I'm like buying me a good, I didn't even think
Jackson: about like managing my subscriptions that are critical to my life.
Tyler: That's like probably the most popular use case that people are showing on social media is like
Tyler: it saved me a bunch of money by going through my personal finances and then like canceling
Tyler: subscriptions automatically or like writing emails to airlines to like chase them down to get some
Tyler: $200 credit that you're owed because they delayed you stuff that used to be very high friction
Tyler: or not even very high, but just friction full enough that people just let it slide.
Tyler: But now it's like you have this guardian that will do all that stuff and doesn't care about
Tyler: it being tedious and annoying. I saw one thing where it was stocks of companies that rely
Tyler: on subscription model where the assumption is that a lot of these subscriptions are like zombies,
Tyler: have gone down a bunch ever since these things launched. Yeah, I do think that the model of
Tyler: interaction for a lot of these flows is going to change. All of customer support is going to
Tyler: change so substantially when you're like, "Oh, I'm never going to email or chat with customer
Tyler: support again because I'm just going to have my agent do it." And it's kind of funny because on
Tyler: on the other side, a lot of customer support chats are already someone else's AI agent,
Tyler: like the company's AI agent. But I think now just the volume of complaints and stuff like that,
Tyler: that these companies are going to get, they're going to have to figure out new protocols and new
Tyler: ways to conduct business to accommodate these kind of new things that have popped up.
Chris: Yeah, it's, I mean, the volume of everything is exploding, right? Every like kind of text data.
Chris: And I think like that filtering function is, is going to be maybe one of the biggest problems
Chris: for existing institutions going forward. On the privacy note, I think like,
Chris: in a lot of ways, language models have changed, like, the way that I think about what privacy is.
Chris: And I'll give you an example. There was a paper from ETH Zurich released the other
Chris: day where they created an AI model to de-anonymize anonymous Reddit users, right?
Chris: And this model was fantastic. I think it had like, you know, 60 or 70% efficacy.
Tyler: bias, eith, zurich, banking, eye models that de-anonymize people, don't they have,
Tyler: like, I don't know, like, burn rate policies to bike shed about?
Chris: Yeah, I, you know, you would think that, but I think this is a different
Chris: Ethereum account. Sorry, it's a, it's a Swiss, the Swiss version of this. I don't think it's,
Chris: I don't think it's the classical black shedding eth.
Tyler: But it's associated with Ethereum research.
Chris: The University in Zürich in Switzerland, ETH.
Chris: I think it stands for ETH Zürich.
Jackson: Yeah, now I have the same confusion, Tyler.
Jackson: Because one of the articles I read for an earlier podcast
Jackson: was from this university as well.
Tyler: Yeah, and I thought it was just like some like a Ethereum foundation research org.
Chris: Okay, so the worst thing about this is they do publish a lot of cryptography,
Chris: and they have some of the best cryptographers in the world. So there's a lot of overlap.
Tyler: Yeah, I think that's why I think it's used because I've seen a lot of their output in that domain.
Tyler: That's totally fine. Apologies to the August institution of ETH.
Chris: I think it's ETH. I think I should, I maybe should have said ETH.
Jackson: We should just call it Ethereum. It's, it's Vitalik's, like, you know, Vitalik University.
Chris: So Ethereum Zurich has been doxxing people.
Chris: But yeah, anyway, so like, you know, they had, you know, fantastic success,
Chris: success, basically finding out who people are behind anonymous posts on hack and use
Chris: and Reddit with this model that, and you know, I think these are only going to get better.
Chris: Famously, actual ETH guy Vitalik put out a bounty on a post that he published a long
Chris: time ago, saying like, if you can find this post that I had pseudonymously published,
Chris: you know, based only on my writing style, then I'll give you a bounty and it was also
Chris: found by a model. And the quirk of that one was it was written in Chinese, and just like very
Chris: heavily obfuscated. So I think like, you know, there's this famous rune post that says like,
Chris: are you ready for everything to become legible? And I think like, the capabilities of these models
Chris: unlock, I think like things that people thought were private or adequately private, I think that
Chris: that just goes away, you know, in the next couple of years, I
Chris: think a lot of stuff comes out. And, and I don't know how
Chris: people are going to deal with that. But I suspect, yeah,
Chris: there's gonna, there's gonna have to be a social change. You
Chris: know, on like, how we think about how we think about
Chris: privacy, and what's private.
Tyler: So have you changed anything in your, like, online operations,
Tyler: like how you interact with the internet in accordance with this?
Chris: I post with my face. Uh, so I think, like, yeah,
Chris: so I've, I've had pseudonymous alts before. Um, but I,
Chris: I think like, it seems like that's,
Chris: I'm going to use this at least for a little while going away.
Tyler: ATH model to go find Chris's old accounts.
Chris: Uh, yeah, good luck. Um, it's, uh, anything is possible. Uh,
Chris: But, uh, but yeah, I think like, yeah.
Chris: And I think you do kind of see this with these pseudonymous posters as well,
Chris: who are like, have slowly revealed more parts of their identity.
Chris: And now it's like a capital pseudo pseudonymous, uh, for a lot of these people.
Chris: Um, if an LLM can find Satoshi, I didn't even think I would want that, but,
Chris: uh, that would be scary.
Jackson: And having worked in like fraud for like three or four years, it just made me see how interacting
Jackson: with the internet at all is like quite exposing even beyond like your writing style through
Jackson: all the markers that like your computer is sending through the network and is available
Jackson: to every website that you visit.
Jackson: So I've always felt like it's, it's kind of fruitless to try to be anonymous because
Jackson: the effort you'd have to go through to obfuscate all the markers and truly be like, secure
Tyler: is like a lot, a lot more than browse the web from to our browser on your Tails OS laptop
Tyler: that you bought at Best Buy using only cash while wearing a COVID mask?
Chris: Hey man, we all went through a, yeah, we all went through a bovad arch Linux phase. Okay. Like it's,
Chris: let's not, it's not fire too many shots. All right. It was university. It was a different time.
Jackson: Do we know why LLMs unlocked this ability to trace writing styles? Like why couldn't we
Jackson: And we have done this before.
Tyler: I mean, I think there was a whole academic field of like, what is it?
Tyler: Stigonometry or something.
Chris: Did I just butcher that?
Tyler: Stigonography.
Tyler: Stigonometry.
Tyler: It's like trigonometry, but with words.
Tyler: Yeah, this was a whole like academic field, I believe, for a long time.
Tyler: But I guess the models are just way better at it than any kind of like, you know, word
Tyler: frequency based kind of statistical methods, I assume, or what they were previously doing.
Jackson: So like an LLM is just a mastered sternographer out of the box. And you don't have to like
Jackson: augment it in any custom way. Or it didn't like discover new sternographic methods that are now
Jackson: employed. It's just like a little genius. Is that what I'm saying? I think intuitively,
Chris: It feels like LLMs are really good at like noticing things and patterns and rules, right?
Chris: And I think like when you're de-anonymizing someone, it is like looking for patterns and rules in
Chris: you know, how they behave or like how they type or stuff like that. So that would be my guess.
Jackson: Cool. Yeah. Thank you for bringing that up, Chris. That was a not on the docket,
Jackson: but a beautiful, a beautiful tangent and an exciting thing to learn.
Chris: every time you type on the internet. Yeah, what could I say? I just hate privacy, you know,
Chris: I think open kimono. That's after Tyler said it last part, I think we have to embrace it.
Tyler: Yeah, but I'm like a guy who's like, Oh, I use like proton mail as like my primary thing. And
Tyler: now I'm like, Oh, I also have an old Gmail that like half of my friends and my mom still send
Tyler: email to my Gmail because they like don't acknowledge proton mail as a valid email destination.
Tyler: Their email is Gmail. Their brains just break if I give people an email that doesn't end in
Tyler: gmail.com. It would be a lot easier if I just started using that sucker again and just hooked
Tyler: up agent of choice to it. Oh, you're really slip sliding. Okay.
Chris: I still have a course on mail, but if you go, I might go too.
Tyler: Oh, I haven't pulled the ripcord yet. Okay. Yeah.
Jackson: We've got something really exciting developing in Bitcoin, or not developing, but an interesting
Jackson: proposal. Shielded Bitcoin. Tyler, resident Bitcoin expert. Is shielded Bitcoin legit?
Tyler: It's hard to say. Where did you come across this proposal? Because I see that it was like a paper
Tyler: that was released. And there was one post on delving about it. And the post was like,
Tyler: open discussion on shielded Bitcoin. And then it had no responses yet.
Tyler: So it's a little bit hard to like generate a take on something that's like a wizard tier topic.
Tyler: And then like, you don't have any of the wizards like weighing in and being like,
Tyler: this is interesting. But like, have you you know, has this flaw or something like usually a lot of
Tyler: the people who weigh in initially find things wrong with something. But yeah, okay, as far as
Tyler: I can tell, this is a new proposal to add a private pool of coins onto Bitcoin. And I think that the
Tyler: thing that they claim it does is that you can move Bitcoin on L1, essentially, while maintaining
Tyler: privacy, you don't have to kick it until like an L2 or anything like that.
Tyler: And I'm not quite sure how they do it.
Tyler: It sounds a little bit to me like state chains, or at least that's my model of state chains,
Tyler: although state chains requires a state chain operator, and it has some downsides associated
Tyler: with that, which is that the state chain operator can be part of your transaction, and then
Tyler: they're able to kind of track it.
Tyler: And so you kind of trust that you're not transacting against the state chain operator.
Tyler: And this one, they make it sound more peer to peer.
Tyler: Yeah, so this is what my agent pulled up on this.
Tyler: This proposal describes private transfers using encrypted notes and proofs with data
Tyler: published through Bitcoin. Users or indexers separately reconstruct and validate the shielded
Tyler: system. So it sounds like a CSV type protocol, which is client side validation. So it's kind
Tyler: of like a meta protocol on top of Bitcoin as far as I can understand it. But yeah, the other thing
Tyler: that the agent pointed out, it goes, "The crucial limitation, the paper leaves peg-in and peg-out
Tyler: outside of its scope," which I feel like that's the hardest part of any of these systems,
Tyler: basically always. And so, I don't want to say, "Day on arrival," and this will never happen,
Tyler: but I feel like that's a very important piece you won't have to figure out before you could
Tyler: actually have anything like this live. So as far as I can tell, this seems like really cool
Tyler: research and something I love to see options getting pushed in that direction. But I don't
Tyler: think we're going to see like good privacy on Bitcoin layer one because of this anytime soon.
Tyler: I guess one benefit that is claimed in this is that it doesn't require any kind of new
Tyler: functionality. So it doesn't need any kind of soft work or anything like that in order to
Tyler: operate. But yeah, I would also just kind of contrast this with something like Arc Protocol,
Tyler: which I think actually provides pretty good privacy to users of the protocol right now,
Tyler: especially if more people use it, the anonymity set gets bigger and bigger.
Tyler: And that is a scheme where you can basically transact in Bitcoin, essentially privately and
Tyler: and cheaply off-chain and you have unilateral exit
Tyler: to claim a UTXO on L1, whatever you want.
Tyler: And so if something like that exists,
Tyler: there's probably still some benefit
Tyler: in having more privacy on Bitcoin layer one.
Tyler: But yeah, I don't quite know how this thing would work.
Chris: - I think this comes at a really interesting time
Chris: with the large language models making things legible thing,
Chris: I've noticed this narrative around like,
Chris: okay, privacy is going to be super important now
Chris: because anyone can look up any transaction
Chris: and maybe find things that you otherwise
Chris: wouldn't have noticed to like correlate things
Chris: back together and like undo transactional privacy,
Chris: even if it's like a separate UTXO or like,
Chris: whatever you're doing, us spinning up new addresses.
Chris: Yeah, like I've noticed that people talking a lot
Chris: this, you know, in this paper and also around Zcash. But yeah. Yeah, man. I just I just don't know.
Chris: I don't know which way this is going to go. I get the impression that privacy is going to be very
Chris: important. But I will like, are we are we too late? Like, you know, it doesn't matter. Do these
Chris: anonymity sets matter in the world of language models? Or like, you know, can can they be on
Tyler: wound. I don't know. Yeah, I feel like my mental model of player ones was already that they're so
Tyler: surveilled because there's three to five multi-billion dollar companies that all they do is
Tyler: sell blockchain surveillance to governments and corporations. And they're really good at it.
Tyler: And they do a lot of stuff to gather extra data on top of what appears in the blockchain.
Tyler: And I think that that is actually a lot of their competitive advantage is that they do
Tyler: a lot of kind of shady shit where they will like have honeypot nodes, they'll like basically
Tyler: a clip stack some nodes where like they'll just be trying to peer with everyone and like
Tyler: maybe a majority of your peers are like a blockchain surveillance firm or something
Tyler: like that.
Tyler: They run like fake block explorers and like log all of the IPs of people that visit them
Tyler: and then they can associate those IP addresses. They could run public Electrum server. And
Tyler: then the same thing, associate queries for specific IP addresses or pubkeys with IPs.
Tyler: And so, yeah, I do think that probably the legibility thing will only get worse from
Tyler: here. But also, you should already assume that everything you're doing on Bitcoin or
Tyler: Ethereum or any L1 is totally accessible to any entity fully linked up unless you're
Tyler: very strong with your op-sec and your hygiene and your privacy with these things, which
Tyler: it's really, really hard to do.
Tyler: And it's really, really hard to do that over the course of years and years and years and
Tyler: years because you forget what you did with that wallet in the past.
Tyler: You forget where that UTXO came from.
Tyler: You slip up once and then it undoes all of your prior careful activity and OPSEC.
Tyler: And so it's just really hard to do this stuff correctly.
Chris: Totally.
Chris: You know, I spoke to someone recently who was talking a bit about physical Bitcoin as
Chris: a way to disrupt sort of like the transaction providence of the Bitcoin.
Chris: You know, like if you're handing a like a paper wallet or something between people as
Chris: like a spendable currency.
Chris: I think there are like some famous versions of this that like were early on that were
Chris: like poker chips or coins.
Chris: Yeah, it's interesting.
Chris: I think there are a lot of approaches to this and I'm really not sure whether privacy becomes
Chris: more important and people like freak out or privacy becomes less important and people,
Chris: know, let go of some parts of things and say, okay, actually, like, you know, this
Chris: is not that private and I don't care that much.
Tyler: Yeah, I mean, I think just moving to a system where a lot of the transactions are
Tyler: published on a blockchain. And there's like a lot of layer two constructions where
Tyler: that's the default. I think that gets you a long way. Like Lightning Network, for
Tyler: example, does that where you basically only settle like the end state of the channel balance.
Tyler: Like I said earlier, Arc does that to some extent.
Tyler: CK rollups would do that, I think quite excellently, if I understand correctly,
Tyler: because even the operator of the rollup chain doesn't see any details of the transaction.
Tyler: They just get the proof and the proof does nothing. And so if you're not creating that
Tyler: toxic waste to start with, then you can't expose the toxic waste to other parties.
Tyler: So, I wouldn't be completely black-pilled about this stuff. I feel like the tech could
Tyler: get there. I'm almost more black-pilled about people's desire to use them. And then the
Tyler: regulatory climate for any of them, should they provide good privacy, then you see the
Tyler: governments basically pressure exchanges to not support that coin because that coin is tainted.
Tyler: It's only used by criminals, that kind of thing. And that's how you kind of stigmatize it and make
Tyler: it not viable. So I think that's more of a problem almost than the technological solutions in some
Chris: ways. Right. Which for the audience is what happened to the privacy coins in 21, 22 era
Jackson: exchanges with pressure to deal with some. Yeah, just a reminder that sending Bitcoin
Jackson: is not anonymous. And that's the only reason the government let's us keep using it. And
Jackson: thank you, Tyler. I knew the shielded Bitcoin thing came up last minute. Maybe we'll get
Jackson: some wizardry, pardon me wizardry in the next week and learn a little more. But maybe this
Jackson: is just nothing. But it did spark a very important conversation on privacy and just a reminder
Jackson: of the surveillance state that we live within. Moving into our final topic of the evening,
Jackson: of the day is conspiracy theories on why we are pacing the frontier.
Jackson: Number one of which is, uh, your favorite Berkeley.
Chris: Oh, we're doing talking about this.
Jackson: All right.
Jackson: Okay.
Jackson: Let's go.
Jackson: Let me open.
Jackson: Your favorite Berkeley sex orgy club doesn't like AI or is scared of AI and is the determining
Jackson: voice on the safety of it.
Jackson: How legit is this idea?
Jackson: Did you guys read the article that was really, really long and hard to follow?
Chris: I skimmed it.
Chris: I don't personally take like enormous amounts of interest in that subject matter, but I've, you know, like I've, you know, I'm aware of effective altruists and I think anyone who has been in crypto since FTX, you know, has met a few.
Chris: And yeah, I thought it was I think it's like it's a plausibly interesting article about maybe the
Chris: connections behind the EA x risk people and like how they all are very close. But the article struck
Chris: me as it as being a like, not very well written and be written by someone who is maybe a little
Chris: bit upset. So I take it with a grain of salt. But yeah.
Tyler: Yeah. There was an article that went viral on X today by somebody that was basically,
Tyler: it was like a hit piece on EA and like AI doomers, essentially. And the main
Tyler: thrust of the article was that the AI doomer whole clique basically is just like one group
Tyler: of people that all reside in Berkeley and they are all rationalists, they're all effective
Tyler: altruists.
Tyler: They have the same like sexual proclivities which are very like libertine and they live
Tyler: together in communes. And basically, they're just saying that like, this is a cult. And
Tyler: if you look at it by any other way, it's a cult. I don't think that it necessarily engaged
Tyler: with like the ideas of like why they think AI poses existential risk. It was more just
Tyler: like these people are all the same people. This is like a monoculture of thought. And
Tyler: all like true believers and they believe this with like the fervency of a religion. And
Tyler: then also there's like a lot of weird sexual angles involved. So yeah, there's a lot there.
Chris: Well documented at this point.
Tyler: Yeah, I wouldn't say that like these people like, yes, like the anthropic as a company
Tyler: has like deep EA ties. And they're the ones who like recently kind of revived this idea
Tyler: of pacing the frontier. But like the conspiracy theory that I see more online is that like,
Tyler: oh, this is a convenient business move. And like you're pacing the frontier to like,
Tyler: you know, do something advantageous for your business because you're afraid of Chinese open
Tyler: bottles, or you want to scare the government into giving you a regulatory arbitrage monopoly,
Tyler: all of this kind of stuff. And I don't think that those things really play into this
Tyler: article that's more about these people are pretty out there and they've been out there for a decade.
Tyler: And I don't think that has anything to do with these big AI companies
Tyler: trying to protect their businesses. I think that these people really believe what they believe,
Tyler: but I think the main takeaway also is just that they have extremely non-conventional
Tyler: beliefs across the board. Does that discredit any of those individual beliefs? Not necessarily,
Chris: but it's an interesting read. I think with any cults across the board,
Chris: or with many cults. You know, there are cynical people who are potentially taking advantage of
Chris: the cult, right? Like maybe the cult leader or people at the upper echelons of the cult.
Chris: But cults require true believers to make the thing function, right? And I'm not saying that
Chris: that's exactly what's happening here, but I would like to present the possibility that
Chris: effective altruists who are like in these shared group houses who do substantially make up AI
Chris: safety researchers like it is a very non trivial portion of them do believe exactly what they're
Chris: saying like I really I wouldn't doubt that but that there are other you know maybe potentially
Chris: more cynical parties or more pragmatic parties who you know can see that opportunity and take
Chris: advantage of it if it is beneficial to them. I'm not saying that's exactly what's happening,
Chris: but I want to present an alternative hypothesis here.
Jackson: Thank you. And this is coming from Chris, our resident psychology expert,
Jackson: although cults might be sociology. I'm not sure.
Tyler: What's the closest you've ever been to being in a cult?
Tyler: Me. I feel like Jackson has a good answer for this.
Jackson: No. No, I don't think nothing comes to mind for me.
Jackson: Chris, any opportunities?
Chris: I lived in a very party-oriented share house in Berlin for a little while. And I think that was
Jackson: I was pretty close, but, uh, I did run into a guy and, and college who I had
Jackson: played junior tennis with and like, I didn't know a lot about him besides
Jackson: that I was superior tennis and what else do you need to know about someone?
Jackson: Well, I got to know a lot more about him in college because he came back
Jackson: around into my life, just like for one night and one night I was at a party.
Jackson: was like drinking extremely heavily and this dude is like trying to sell me home security
Jackson: system but like I lived in an apartment in a dormitory so I didn't need it but he kept
Jackson: trying to sell it to me and I was like dude you're in a Ponzi scheme because he's telling
Jackson: me that he had the home security system in his dorm apartment oh it was like a pyramid
Jackson: scheme like a yeah he's like dude you gotta do it and like I mean really
Jackson: everyone should and he was trying to convince me I'm like dude you're an
Jackson: idiot and I want you to shut up all that to say I feel like Ponzi schemes are very
Jackson: similar to the cults where people believe it he believed it and there was
Jackson: nothing I could say to convince him otherwise so I mean if we really want to
Chris: pee back on that resident psychologist thing there's a book called When Prophecy
Chris: fails by Leon Festinger, I think it's 1964, where he invents the concept of cognitive dissonance.
Chris: And he does this by infiltrating UFO cults and seeing what happens when they fall apart.
Chris: And basically, like, half the people leave and half the people double down.
Chris: And I think, you know, that's kind of what we're describing here a little bit.
Chris: I think, you know, great book, everyone should read it. But yeah, yeah, I think it's well known.
Jackson: Well, we covered some conspiracy theories, there's still some other great ones out there,
Jackson: but maybe we'll talk about those next time.
Jackson: Thank you all for coming to our podcast about super intelligence, and I got you next week.